hi good evening how's everyone doing hi muneshwara good good great guys let me share my screen
do let me know if you can see the screen share it was great i mean it was great i think you
can see my dp it was one of the haldis dp i'm not able to share my screen guys give me a
second i need to rejoin the call maybe asa asa i didn't invite it uh it was all like yeah we
would celebrate it if you if you are here nearby hydropad yeah yeah sister's responsibility is very
yeah like it's big man like big thing right here okay sure let's meet someday then some talk or
somewhere and catch up guys i think i have an issue from you know sharing the screen
i'll join back in a minute okay then we'll continue with the class give me a second
you
uh guys recheck again i'm visible audible right uh let me try to share the screen again
hopefully this time it works
so uh did you guys enjoy the teachings by shashwood are you able to catch up with the
concepts that he was able to uh like understand it okay can we share some with uh can we revise
wait once so we'll have uh one whole like three classes for a sink event i will be covering them
in depth something so no need to worry uh we'll be covering them in depth once we
okay do you feel still there is a network issue guys anyone still facing uh facing network issue
feel like there's a network issue
okay in past class okay uh no worries so uh let me try to
rethink okay yeah uh is screen share working fine guys are you able to see
i ask visual studio code being shared cool so let me connect with my ipad too in a minute
we are on time
hey kenny can anyone drop a ping in whatsapp group so that because it's a continuation you know
classes next day classes will be building one project together applying all the concepts i
want everyone to be there so if you have any doubts from the previous sessions we'll be able
to cover that's the reason why i'm pushing bit uh give me a second
so
so you can see you see my ipad too right right great okay uh
uh so can we get started guys are you all excited for one of the final projects
in like from html css javascript point of view one project keeping all of them together in depth
we'll see what how how much we are empowered now to build what sort of projects we can build
okay so we'll try to see of all of them so before that uh give me a second i need to open few of
the sites from my side i have my notes actually written
so does anyone earlier have heard about this keyword called kanban board
board
really anyone came across this keyword called kanban board if yes can you guys tell me like
what is this all about like what do you know about this one like kanban board jeera okay great
anything else guys
so guys are you able to hear a fan sound you want me to shut it down
uh is my voice clear
okay great great so jeera now so did anyone came across something called to do list in their life
any applications that you see related to to do list right so so can i say something like uh
tracking tool of your task
this thing comes under those categories right something which manages your task and whereas
jeera is a uh one product solution a product used to
to manage project development
so this is enterprise based an application where uh you know we have our own to-do list like when
you start a day you might have a certain things to do it uh but when you go for the project level
thing right there are too many things to address too many things to handle so what jeera jeera is
a tool given by atlassian they have prepared to build this one end to end they are the owners
for this one so what they give is they give you an ability to run a project like whole end to end
life cycle like maybe from the inception to the end it will track whole things it will help you
to divide them into sprints have anyone come came across words something like agile or sprints or
anything have you heard of these keywords okay yeah so this is something like a to-do list now
let's let's let's see this like how this works uh let me get the browser open uh give me a second
like let's say if i show you a example of canban board
if you see these are like uh uh like canban board now if you like a simple example is to-do
in progress and testing and done this is a process of a development that happens right
once you are given a task you do complete the development uh like i can open a picture from
here let's see but this picture is visible right uh there should be a picture of the
uh but this picture is visible right uh they're showing me too many advertisements but this
picture like generally it is a an application which helps us to drive the work okay that's an
idea if i show you something that you're talking about uh the tool jeera like this is the tool
like if i go by so this looks like some this way uh if i zoom it in uh let's say if i zoom it in
uh if you see this in jeera also they have to-do in progress in review and done so there are four
stages for everything there is a four stages now we we are going to build some you know a prototype
which is uh based on this like uh an inspiration from this uh a board which will help us to you
know manage our task and apply the concepts that we have learned so let me show you the uh you know
a built already built app give me a second i'll launch that app and i'll show you what we are
going to build it projects uh second guys i am trying to launch the app i'm trying to launch
from a different repo as of now so okay this is something a weather app that i launched but
did you guys got you know everyone understood the weather app right how it was built
right okay great now so if you see this is a kanban board that looks like now these are the four
filters firstly this is a navbar section on the top whatever you can see a navbar section so this
is again an inspiration for a to-do list whatever a to-do list with a better features okay uh maybe
you can improve on this but this is what we will be learning where we allow where we'll apply all
the knowledge okay now if you see these other filters firstly in order to create tasks one
user need to click it on a plus once you click it here you will be able to enter whatever information
is related to task let's say if you want to create a task considering scalar life cycle like if you
when i say scalar life cycle uh let's say first thing that you would do is attend the class right
and let's say i select this color pink setting the priority now i'll tell you talk about the
colors that what we have understood what we have decided through these colors you can change to
text later on but now once you select this and i click the shift key uh give me a second
okay this isn't okay now if you see what just happened now i have created a ticket now saying
a ticket now saying that attending a class now if you want to edit this content like editing the
content of a class like whatever task you have you have a lock button once you click a lock button
you would be able to edit the text like you can add anything in jeopardy you want to add
and once you do it you can also lock the back lock it back so that the edit is done this is
working like an edit button okay is that clear guys till now like how can you create a ticket
and how can you uh like edit the ticket so two functionalities one is creating a ticket
editing the ticket now third functionality that i'm talking about is like if you see in the jira
board or the kanban board you have different statuses like to do in progress in review undone
now how we are managing them in our application that we are going to build is that like if you
see this pink color bar if i click it it is going to green then it is going to sky blue then it is
going to black okay so we are saying that whenever we are moving it from one status to other status
it generally meant that we are moving the task like let's say task from this stage to this stage
this stage to this stage like one stage to the next stage is that clear guys like what this color
palette is talking about like whenever you are clicking here you are able to change the color
and update the status of the task that you have created now once let's say once you have created
yeah we can we can add multiple tasks i'll show that once you have created you also have an
ability to delete the task how can you delete it in order to enable the delete right in order to
enable the delete first you have to click cross button once you have let's say when you click the
cross button delete button has been activated it says now once it is delivered and activated
you go on anything and click on it like on a whole other task anywhere you click it it will be deleted
like again you can stop the delete button okay again is that clear how delete works
now let's try to create a multiple task let's say let's say i say this as a task one okay pink
status and now task one is done let's say i create again a task two okay
uh let's say i edit it i add content as task two
and i close it now let's say i have something like task three now let's say i'm clicking the
shift key guys that's why the ticket has been created but i'll show you why i uh choose switch
uh shift key instead of enter key for creating a task but i'm just like now i'm trying to create
multiple tasks task four uh and pink and shift key okay now if you see this i've created four tasks
now let's say i move the task one to in progress let's say green is something like in progress
and we have sky blue and let's say this is green in color now let's say this is completed if i move
to black it is meant to be completed now when you move this way uh like when i move this way now if
you want to filter out which are the in progress tasks like you need filter right uh what are the
completed what are in progress what i have complete like status if you want to see filter by the
status now these are the filters like if i click the pink i'll be only able to see the one task
if i if i want to see only like green i'll be able to see this task if i want to see sky blue
i will be able to see one task if i select black i'll be able to see this one but if i refresh
now i'm able to see all the task is that clear guys how filter works
yeah yeah yeah yeah kiran that's that's where i'll give you a lot of homework and task for you to in
order to improve this application i'll give you as many uh pointers that you can work on because i
want you to you know paste this in your resume uh improving this application because this task
is also borders are not clean you can make it that instead of this delete button you can
delete button you can give edit button actually but i'm giving you the knowledge and functionality
it's up to you how you want to make it much more experience a better experience application
okay how can you improve the experience okay now the another thing that we are going to learn here
is that if you see even after a refresh right we are able to persist the data right any guesses
guys how we are able to persist this data like if you see even if i'm refreshing the task i created
somewhere i'm storing in memory those are not being refreshed those variables those tickets
are stored somewhere any guesses where yeah database is a right thing and in browser we have
certain kind of databases like as some bit says there's something like local storage that is what
we are going to explore here if you see here if you come here in the applications part there's
something called as local storage which we will be using to store the stickers if i expand this one
if you see i have four tasks for four tasks i'm having the color task information in the ticket
id ticket id is a dynamic id first create generated for each task you create is that clear like what
we are going to learn and what what what's context of this project is like did you understand the
workflow like what we are able going to build in next three classes now i'm going to take it
everything slowly guys so slowly such that if needed any topic to be revised i'll try to cover
that and you know move ahead step by step okay now let's go back to our ipad write down the things
that we have understood okay now okay now let's say so firstly i'll talk about something like color
priorities that we have created
that colors we have given four colors this is something you can improve on
instead of colors uh no worries i just started talking your project i still didn't code it
anything okay so the colors that we have uh given in the project just will will check the or like
i'll define what they are talking about let's say task which task to be done
like let's say they are in black in color and then we have something like task in progress
then we have something like let's say not by black in color let's make since it's a starting
red light pink and instead of light i'll write green then let's say task to be validated
right blue
task
which are completed
a black in color right so these are the classes like these are the tasks like colors that we have
decided just now i've shown you all the different colors when i say pink in color it means to say
that task is which need to be complete or like start working on once you start working on
anything let's say this is a task is currently working progress so you'll be seeing the green
in color and to be validated task is done but it needs to it's need to be reviewed which is task
one and if it is completed it is black in color are this point clear clear guys like what this
color priorities are talking about now now like i'll talk about some of the you know theory concept
about industry standards about how actually development goes okay let's say i coin this one
as something like industry standard like when you go and join any firm could be a bigger like i'm
talking from a big organization perspective startups may not have those many roles but let's
say if you go from one great organization what how the how does uh you receive and what's your
role going to be in future if you join some good good comp like i don't want to say good company
but a great big company okay now so firstly there are the three teams that are involved
okay one team is called as product then the other team is called ui ux then third time is called def
or engineering team
i hope everyone have heard this keywords earlier right like ui ux engineering team qa
qa comes under dev somewhere so if you come at my office there is no role for qa it's something
that we do it we write automation tests we write unit tests we write we do qa and everything is
done by developers developer when you say all on developer you are responsible for the
features that you are building that's where ownership comes into the role in product
okay so now i'll talk a bit about uh product now product is a team who are actually let's say if i
talk about atlasian jeera right this team jeera team our product team will be discussing like how
can they can add more features or how can they bring uh do better or how can they improve the
existing application so they think from product point of view like what we can add let's say
they are giving us tasks filters editing timeline dates and everything like if we go for instagram
you can update a photo update a video update send a reel create a reel like send messages
so this all like uh you know requirement gathering part those things are done by
product team so these people are someone who gathers requirement
is that clear who is the product team in general i hope everyone
okay
right now once product team gets those requirements right they discuss with something called as
uiuxt these people are responsible to understand these requirements and build something called as
wireframes
or they sometimes say figma screens and figma is a really
industry's uh leader you can say too has anyone came across this keywords wireframes and figma
screens right so once your product information requirements are ready they see how can they
can build user experience when i say user experience i mean to say that
what would be the flow of an application okay then or you can say user interface if it is a
one screen layout okay so once uiuxt is ready requirements are ready then once this all things
are spoon-fitted to us about the requirements and the journey then comes solutioning
by engineering team
so mostly when this wireframes are also built right one of the leads are involved to say what
are the feasibility whatever they give we might not be able to build because we have certain
limitations okay but this engineering team is who builds the idea once this idea is gathered
wireframes are ready we are we are supposed to build it okay is this clear guys like how what
would the actual workflow when it comes to a front end developer or like how does in industry it
works happen works okay so once this is done now let's follow the same process let's follow
the same process uh let's let's say firstly we'll we'll act like uh let's say we are here
wearing a hat of a product we say that we note down product requirements
we'll try to make notes of all the requirements so first can we we need an ability
to create task
and add status to it right
add status to it right
we are able to create task and add status to it like color maybe any color selecting
then ability to edit the task
then ability to filter
task depending on status
then ability to delete the task
so
post-completion
and the final requirement is browser should be
able to
store task
and it should process and data should persist
right these are the features that we have discussed initially right do you guys agree
this is something we are going to build
this has something we are going to build
let's give me some reactions if you agree
so nice so these are the things that we are going to build in all upcoming like next class
in today's class now once this is done let's say this once this product requirement is done we
have something called as wireframes okay now i don't have figma tool or i'm not good at that
but i will design wireframe here in the ipad using my bare hands like just to understand
it what we are going to build okay to just show you what happens in industry okay like
if you see wireframe we have something called as a clean layout let's say i down a bit below
let's say this let's say this is a screen that we have inside the screen we have two things
one is nav bar inside this nav bar we have something like you know a filter color filter
okay now inside this color filter we have four different colors to filter depending on the status
of the task the same way we have two buttons one is like let's say
a plus then a cross now once this is done then we have something like
ticket creation one let's say this is how you can create a ticket inside cricket let's say this is a
ticket firstly you have ticket status then you have a unique task id then you have content of
the task okay when you go for like when you go for creating a ticket let's say you have here
where you can enter the information then you have four colors okay now let me write down all
those things what this is talking about okay firstly this is something like let's say if i
say toolbox because this is allowing us giving us a multiple tools or you can also say navbar
okay this is create a ticket button
okay and this is enable delete
ticket functionality ticket button let's say right then these are the filters
then you will have something like ticket status
here you have ticket id
let's say ticket content
here you have something like enter your task
like enter your task
like let's say task content
then parallelly you'll have status of the task
right this is how y-frame looks like this is what we are going to build isn't it
like on a top level what if there is no ticket what if there is no ticket then you won't be
able to see this one and this one both when so it's just that what what are the all possibilities
things they give you you try to sit with them and understand it and then you get started okay
okay
now once this is clear we'll get started with you know what is the third task guys
once your product requirements are ready wireframes are ready to start with the dev work
okay now so in the development part let's say
okay
we'll cover today developing the screen we'll develop whole the screen
and we'll do css part html part we'll get started with one small functionality using js
but we'll pick we'll pick functionalities one by one in the later stages is that clear guys
what is going to be today's agenda from the development point of view
great now it's time to get started with project okay
okay
great so let me move to vs code give me a second guys
right
okay
now i created a subsection in the projects i'll be supposed to move weather app inside this i'll
reset some of the changes i'll make some changes in the repo but firstly i'm creating three simple
files index.html style.js then let's say
sorry style.css
then let's say i have script.js okay now let's go to index.html
and create some simple html let's say this one as can band board
once we have defined the scan band board now let's connect this you know styles using link tag
so i have give relation as a style sheet and also i'm trying to link style.css using the current
okay now in let's say i just to review this one right i'll have a one div container
inside that i'll say can band board i'll open this in the live server
okay let me go back the browser
so this is our project as of now okay now so firstly what we'll do is that we'll try to target
building something called as this snapper sort of thing that you can see it here
okay we'll focus on that one now let's say when when we are focusing on this we'll say this
as a container a container called toolbox container now let's say i have div
toolbox container when i say this and i click enter
oh once i click this enter now once if in this we have two things in this we have two things if
you see from the wireframe or the perspective here you have something filter and now one action
buttons now let's create this two other containers inside this okay one thing we'll call it as
toolbox priority container so like we're filtering it based on priority so i'll say
priority content this is one day then we have something like second thing is called action
button container because we are we are acting on it whether creating a ticket or you know
giving an ability to delete a ticket right so these are the two dips inside this now
once we create these two dips now what we'll do is that inside this we have four colors
right four colors are different palette colors so for this one what i'll do is like i'll just
create four simple dips with different css classes i can say light pink
and let's say i can also say deaf dot light green
then i can also say they've got light blue then i can also say they've got black
okay so if you see what i've done here i just created the four things that we have if you can
see here we don't we don't see anything on the screen but what we can do is we can create
anything on the screen but what we can do is like if you want to see anything on screen you can write
pink green blue or black let's say instead of this one i'll say completed
then to be validated
okay in progress
to be done okay now if you see i say four things here but let's try to make them but let's add some
css to it okay what i'll do is i'll divide them into two screens such that you know we can we'll
be able to see it parallely i'll close this one i'll close this one as of now i hope screen is
visible right guys to everyone
okay done so now we'll get started with a few of the css okay now one of the first thing
you guys have to explain to me if i write two things what i'm generally trying to address it
okay let's say i write universal selector hash trick and then i say something like box sizing
to be border box and let's say i give margin as zero then padding as zero
can anyone help me out what is this all about
what this will do
what's this box sizing border box or margin padding does
is remove the default css which are coming and try to you know address width and height
whatever i'm giving it don't add it separately right like hope that concept is clear now if
you see it is starting from top left exactly without no space like to be done okay now going back
next thing if you see here in the firstly like this all this task like to be filters are coming
in horizontal line isn't it firstly first and first most thing and we know how we can convert
a vertical divs into horizontal guys can you help me out with that
okay now let's say i'm writing a you know separator so that you can remember it now
for display effects i should select this class right toolbox container inside the toolbox once
i click this and i do display as flex once i do this but by default flex direction is zero so
by default flex direction is zero so it should be converted into row let's try to review this
okay this uh it didn't work uh maybe i did i mess up okay i need to apply onto this one
not that one right okay if you see go and see these are converted into horizontal
is that clear guys like this is really basic one that you have suggested me but now what i'll do
is that uh firstly i'll add two toolbox so that we can see all the things that we are applying
okay some of the default styles i'll give it i hope you will be able to understand that one
so first thing i'll do is like if you see one of the uh like i'll add something like a background
color okay and i'll give something like hash uh 4b 4b 4b okay
okay now once i give this black background color let's see this this is coming as a background
now let's say i give some this parameter you need to explain me what is the value in terms of pixels
if i give it as a fire what could be the value in terms of pixel
what would be the value of in terms of pixel for fire
let's think of this one
yeah 16 into 5 80 pixel right so i hope everyone understand when i write rem what i exactly meant
in terms of pixel okay now now if you see this particular task right this particular task
are having two containers now let's say i i go to the other container let's say we have some
differentiation right like if you see this hash color uh this ash color this hash color a bit
different there's some change color change so let's do that okay firstly i'll go and select
this action button container let's pick this up and
okay let's pick this up now inside this container what i'll do is like again i'll give some height
let's say give it height as a uh let's say uh firstly i'll give a height to this container
firstly to visualize this one say height as 3.5 rem then i'll also give a background color to it
a common background color for both one hash 3d 3d a 3d a better darker version that was a 4d 4d
4d this one was a 3d now in order to keep this both boxes same i'll give same 3.5 rem and
background color as like hashtag 3d 3d 3d okay let's save this and if you see you're not able
to reflect this one isn't it we'll see that why it is not happening exactly because it is
completely consuming box as of now we'll come to this step by step okay now
once we did this uh let's say i gave also i'll have some width to each of the item let's say i
have width in terms of 18 which is really big unit but we'll see if this is suiting us suiting
in right way now after being display flex if i need to put them uh let's say if i go back okay
okay this there's something that happened uh let me zoom out a bit it's a 250 pixel uh no
uh we won't be able to see it right away let's do something guys firstly i'll comment this for
some time now if you go back and see you can you guys see this like uh if i try to
these are the four boxes content that we are able to see and we gave that a particular height
and a background color and we made display flexor center but do you see this content is aligned
as we needed like this is in between right if you see from the y-axis point of view it is in the
center isn't it from the y-axis point of view now how can we move that into the center from y-axis
from y-axis how can we move that from y-axis as a center anybody
align items right let's make align items as center no let's see this if this is working
now do you see this there's a space in top there's a space in bottom too isn't it
the space in top and so is in bottom too now second thing do you see space equally equally
distributed on the left and right of each color left and right of each color equally distributed
equally distributed left and right color for that on the horizontal axis we'll do justify
content i wouldn't be doing it to center some bit because
space event rightly rightly said so you have space around space between space evenly when
you go for evenly it will be evenly around each box space around i'll show you the difference
of space around also like but can you see this uh now let's say i go
and let's say let's wait let's try to uh firstly let's give some color to it let's remove these
names as of now the width is not enough uh and what i'll do it here is that in order to improve
this one just addressing width will be fine but i'll try to address uh yeah space around can be
used too but i'll come to why why i'm going with uh space evenly some okay now let's do something
let's do something we have this colors right let's give them some colors okay let's take this class
light pink uh inside this color i'll give something like background color
i'll say background color for the light pink uh let's say light pink
okay now after that you have a light
green background color as light green okay once you have this then you have light
blue once you do this let's say background color
uh light blue
okay now then let's say i i say something like uh black
background color to black
okay now what we have done here is that just now we have given some background colors and
i know uh to each of them i'm getting a call guys
okay uh go back now if you see there is no color being applied why kiran says that we haven't provided
uh like height and width we can use it some that we can use it you can you can build customize your
result experience as as you need it so we have to give height and width to each of the box so what
experience as as you need it so we have to give height and width to each of the box so what i'm
doing is that since height and width for each of the box will be same as we see in the uh like
you know prototype app that we have i'll try to add a common css color class here let's say i
create a class as a color okay
inside this color i'll just go and say hey to all classes which have property as color
we'll add some color now let's say i i i mean i mean to say we want to give height let's say
let's say 1.5 rem since each uh this whole container is 3.5 rem i'm taking 1.5 rem as a height
and let's say i also take some width for it uh let's say it as a 3 rem since 18 rem is whole
space we have i have four boxes in it i'm seeing that 12 rem of boxes and other spaces around
between them and around them okay now let's say let's see if this is working fine
okay this is clear guys how i'm able to replicate and build this one
because you yourself has suggested me how we can build it it's nothing as nothing unique thing i
have done here okay as i told you it's a revision of all the concepts we have learned we'll apply
all of them now but do you see there's something happening here when i hover over it there's some
color is coming on when i'm hovering over each of the palette right do you see this
right so we'll try to uh you know try to work on that part now let's say we go and say hey
on color hover whenever you hover over the color i want to give a different background
so i'm using a pseudo selector color then i'm going for the background color and let's say
i say something like hashtag four eight five four six zero okay now
now let's see if i'm if you see this this is up line is this fine guys how this is working
this is up line is this fine guys how this is working
yeah great now
now i want to show you something i want to show you something like if you see this colors right
if you see color uh is being duplicated this 4b 4b did we use anywhere no
uh toolbox container we use 3d 3d here okay i'll come to that part when we replicating the color
okay now but we have completed till now the css and html part for this particular thing now we
haven't moved them down but if you see we haven't moved them down or aligned according to this
aligned according to this particular thing right this navbar background so how can we do that
which part is preferred kiran i would say go with the css part because mostly pseudo
selectors are given for that reason itself js is compiled and executed later on later of the time so
it's better if you can give it with css because ultimately when you try to do act like hover
it is come it is converted into css then rendered onto the screen
thinking from the thinking from the part of rendering perspective guys coming back to my
question if you see here this is not aligned as we needed from the top or the left side can we do
something here to fix this one can we do something here to fix this one let's say if i go back here
into the toolbox container can we make it them display flex and align items to the center
so that there's a vertically centered right for if you see after applying that now i if you see
here some let's say this is fine we'll come to horizontal one in a second you can always you can
give also like justify content uh let's say for a while let's give justify content as uh space
space space evenly fine works now since you have only one event you won't be able to
like if you see this it moved into center but we'll address this one slowly but is this fine
guys any doubt till now any doubt till now what we have built did anyone face any challenge
understanding this one okay great now now i'm going to introduce guys uh
one thing uh like anyone heard a word called font awesome font awesome
did anyone came across word font awesome okay let's say if i go to font awesome i'll give this site
uh
okay so
guys the here i want you to you know take the site and do one thing like enter your email id
and send embedded code kit okay just if you see it here if you just see it below you will be able
to see the steps that we are supposed to do okay we are we are supposed to do okay what it will
does it like it will give you once you enter that as per your email id it will give you one script
tag i mean you don't really need it but if you are customizing it's supposed to be you generate
your own script tag from the font awesome site you can do it i can help you in the doubt session
if anyone want to screen share it because i already have it i'm not trying i'm not able to
you know redo that step is that fine guys it's just that you know the same things are written
here in the steps two steps first two steps okay so what i'll do it here is that i'll paste that
same script that you will be able to generate it this you will be able to generate it kit.font
awesome.com and this is my id and i'm trying to download the javascript code this is like
dynamic id and the file the you know file name is dynamic file that i'm getting okay this is
something you'll be generating it now once you do this once you do this if you go to icons icons
page and you try to search here like let's say if you see here we need something like plus icon and
cross icon okay if you see here we need plus and cross icon something here it's like you also have
our docs in order to explore you know all the different things like what are the things that
you need like like you can say that use a kit how can you start with the kit you will get the
information completely explore this one this is just you know a freelance website which allows you
to use yeah it's a freelance website open so like where it where you are allowed to use icons
okay free icons because you cannot design icons right for each of your own project
so let's say if i'm giving as a plus and i try to do a google search if you see here i'm able to
get all the plus icons can you see this there are some of the free versions some of the pro versions
if i select this first free version when i click here it if you see i'll be having multiple filters
that i can play around with like making it sharp making it classic if you see if i'm making a
classic i'm getting a rounded edges if i'm making it sharp i'm getting as this one okay and also you
can you know change it a light like what type of plus you want so it gives you all the abilities
all the abilities to do it and you can also as per your project you can also import it
currently we are dealing with only html what i'll do is like i'll try to copy this tag
once i click it here the tag will be copied so i tag goes for icon tag okay so once i go here
and i try to create a sub def and the desk day will talk as like let's say add
button inside this add button i'll try to paste this italic tag
uh let's say i try to show it properly
okay so this is fa solid fa plus so when i say solid it's in solid color filled color
and talking about fa plus now can you see this fa plus being generated here guys
so are you able to follow what font why i am using font also in my you know i'm using those
icons and how would you be able to do it in case anyone faces challenge do let me know
uh how can you import it okay you have to custom download the kit and then you can use it okay
okay now after this plus i have something like a remove sign let's say
let's i say cross
so go for remove itself
cancel yeah let's pick this x marks this is what we need now again i'm trying to copy this
uh cancel yeah wonderful now if you see uh i'll go here again i'll create a def dot
remove button or delete button you can say i am trying to paste it here now once we have this
let's go to kanban board if you see this we are again getting them in a vertical
way now again same display flex once you apply them it will be converted to horizontal
now going back something that we commented earlier i'll try to enable that
and i'll try to push it up between i and i apply display as flex
okay align items so do we need an aligned items here guys
think of it i don't need an alignment as of now but if you see this is how the box is created
this is the kind of box that we are expecting
okay now what could be the next thing now if you see
now let's say for the both the child elements for the both this child elements
we want to add some common properties we want to add for both of the child elements some common
properties now just a question if i don't have a class like let's say class but for the all the
children elements if i want to add some default properties how can i do that
anyone what type of selector i can use it
i want to add it to all the child children selector right now how that children selector looks like
anyone
greater than symbol right greater than now for the greater than symbol now if you see for this action
button i want to give some common properties to all the child can i say hashtag since it's a when
i say universal selector i would say that all the children to this parent element will apply
this particular things isn't it is this point clear guys now same thing we can also do it here
if you see color we added color here as a common property we can also remove this and we can say
like instead of this color we can also say toolbox priority container
let's say we can also say toolbox creative container and also sorry guys
this both things are same isn't it
pardon me so it's always it's an uh you know i'm just trying to show you what are possibilities
again so i added at one place a common color at one place i'm using a children selector
combinatorics okay here now for each of this plus and minus will add since it's these are
containers we are supposed to give them a certain width and height okay now let's give them a width
now if you see it here these are consuming 50 50 percent of width of this parent container right
50 50 percent of parent container exactly 50 50 this one 50 this one you know so let's do that
let's give width as a 50 once we give this uh now and when it comes to height let's say once we give
this now once we give this 50 50 if i give height let's say if i'm giving height
is 100 percent and let's go and see this one do you see any change here once i apply height
no right so i'll show you something if you see if i go and select this part
like like this add button height and width now so even if i increase let's say height of 200
pixel 2000 pixel this no style height will be applied to this one reason behind for icons right
whatever icons you see this if you want to play around with height you have to play around with
font size because font is something that applies to this one now do you see this like the icons
are getting bigger and smaller
so so if you are applying any if you want to apply height to this but
like icons you have to play around with something called as font size so instead of
height i'll use something like let's say font size
and let's say i use something to them
now do you see that it has taken whatever width it needs
now if you go and see it here if you go and see it here they are properly aligned and consuming
the whole space firstly what i'll do it here is that uh let's move them each of item to the center
to the center along the y-axis and x-axis if you see the both are on the y-axis on the top
let's move them to the center both the sides
align items center justify content center okay once we do this
uh does anything happen here nothing is happening uh did i apply for right place yeah i applied for
the right place
okay let's give a width to this one a default width is also for the height we have given
something so for this one i'll give something like eight rem once i give this width to a trim
if you see these buttons are coming here but this align item justify content is not working
because i didn't give flex right guys so that's how i give flex once i give this this is how it
is working all right now once we have given this now if you see here this color of symbols are
white in color now not in black in color let's do that i go back here and i say for the act this
button two buttons both the buttons color should be white okay now both the colors of the this one
are white okay now is this clear guys whatever we have built till now what we have built till now
okay one thing i'll fix it is that when i'm using display flex like this property let's say i go and
do let's say i select this container and on container if you see i've used space evenly
even if i use space around uh things would be different if i give space between uh there are
between uh there are not exactly as we want it okay there is a common space around both the things
and there's an empty space on the right so this can be done by how we can achieve this case
so you know aligning across the horizontal element is not working but how can we do this
so we have discussed in the box model there's a one property which can help you to move the elements
okay think of it guys
in the box model can i can i see here margin left is equal for both of them
because margin is outside the border isn't it so what i'll say it here is that hey i'll go
onto the top i'll remove this property and i'll use something like let's say for the all the
children inside the toolbox container for all the children whatever children you have give margin left
a certain margin let's say i give four rem
now let's go and see if this is we are able to reflect now are you able to reflect with the
navbar that we have thought of initially building it and we have built it same thing right
and do you see anything missing
no hover right hover is missing now earlier uh someone asked me like can we do hover okay
we can do over using js also uh who was that kiran you are the you are the one right who asked
me like can we we can add hover also to js so i'll do that one hover through js once someone comes
on uh like on a button i'll show you that implementation currently i can add that
uh let's say but i can i'll show that through code too but how we can add it let's say
for the all the things uh we go pick this one or the children i say this uh over
background color let's say green
green let's say i see this color no not green yellow but let's make this as a green
is that clear guys as of now like we have addressed all the things that happen in navbar
but we'll also uh see this how we can do it through code for this point okay now any doubts
till now any doubts till now because i'm going to make some changes i'm going to make some changes
no doubts right no doubts right now let's say have anyone came across this thing
like what if i write colon root
this stack colon root tag anyone seen anywhere
open this is hi he has seen any any idea any idea what this does what this does
so let's see let's see this like if i open in the colon root
uh let's say this opened a new tab colon root
okay uh let's say root selector
uh okay now if you see
they say that it selects a root element which is like a top level element in the css
model which is syscom i'll actually i'm supposed to share your documentation if i had taken the
dom i would have done it but uh i'll i'll show you what what i was talking about now
this is a root tag when you come when you consider a like since you have a dom tree
similarly for css you have com syscom syscom tree for that one initial in the tree right you have
a root parent root element same way you have a root for css now inside the css you can declare
all the types of fields that you want now those can be dynamically utilized like this is like
trying to when you declare something in the root you are trying to reuse it like wherever you have
duplication right whenever you have something like duplication like let's say do you see here
background color four four four b is being duplicated or let's say three b is duplicated
at least 3d 3d is duplicated right this both colors are duplicated right background color
now how can you remove this uh like duplication code what you can say is that it's in going inside
the root what what you will say is that let's say uh background for toolbox once you go and do and
write it down let's say you give this value once you give this value let's say you go you
copy this value and put it here once you give this value what you can do here is that wherever
you want to use that value you can call a function here function is called as where inside that fire
you are you are you should be you would be able to call this background for toolbox
now let's say i go and replicate this one below where i'm using this 3d
sorry above
uh where i was using the here right here
here
is that clear guys like why if we are using root uh what is the use case like generally to avoid
duplication of writing css now if you go and see whether it is working now if you see
still it is working fine isn't it now same way same way uh like let's say i select some of the
colors let's say uh i i'll improve uh like you know uh let's say instead of this light blue
we have some color like let's say i use these two colors guys
hash codes let's say i use this two hash codes now what i'll do here is like going for the blue color
color i'll say that hey where
blue let's say for green i'll use where green i just see i recreated this one to just show you
that hey for how you can use the where uh function uh and you're trying to get all the variables
declared inside the root okay now if you see those colors got changed like green and blue
okay this is fine guys did you understand what i was trying to do here
okay cool so uh this is it about the neighbor guys now if we have to get started with
something called as not something called less but something that we want to build uh when you click
on a plus this particular thing so do you need a break or can we continue
okay we'll build html part of it then we'll take a break
we'll build the html part of it when then after break we'll come back to the css
okay if you if you are okay with my point can give me thumbs up
the html part will be done in five minutes okay then we'll take break okay now let's say
okay okay great uh i see great number amount of thumbs up so let's do one thing uh i minimize
this toolbox toolbox container whole thing now let's go back to another diff called as
model container because this is a model i'll say this as a model container inside this model
container i have two things if you see one is text area and the other one is just what like
color balance simple thing right now for text area i have text area uh let's say text area dot
text area container i'll use this
okay uh for initially i'll keep it as it is whatever the content they have given
i'll remove it as of now i don't need these items okay and i'll add only one thing if you
see go back and see what we have generated here this is a default container called as
enter your task information okay let's add that a placeholder enter your task information
ask information
okay let's see if this is fine yeah we are able to see this fine now after this we have
uh like a color one a different list of colors now let's say i try to uh since those are still
same colors i'll what i'll do is that i'll copy it from here uh which i copied from here i'll
change some css classes from the top here i'll say instead of toolbox i'll say these are priority
colors container
because these are the button clicks and statuses we want we want some unique name here that's the
reason that i'm adding and i'll give some default like in order to change the default css one i'll
change something like uh i'll add this keyword priority color
that's it right guys do you see anything
uh else you can do it here
because this is what we have seen it just a text like text area then a different colors but all
the magic will be done using css you cannot see the colors applied because we have manipulated
the styles of it right
so uh it's moving towards the break now how many minutes break you need it
five would be fine
okay so i'll add a five minutes timer we'll come back in five minutes and
so today i believe we'll be ending class early we'll see that i mean when i say early for
me it's like two hours 20 minutes 15 minutes or 20 minutes something around that
yeah so guys take the break and let's see you see you back
later
you
is everyone back guys
and can we get started
so great
so let's get started with something
you know designing this particular text area itself
now think of it this one
do you see I'm having resizing ability here
like if you see here
I have some ability to resize
do you see that is available here
no right
do you remember
that what we can do in order to remove that
this right
let's let's do that let's do that
so firstly what I'll do is that
I'll add a differentiator
saying
CSS for
ticket creation
container
inside this container I'll select
dot text area
container
inside this text area container let's let's add some CSS classes
now as you suggested first thing that I do is like resize none
once I do this resize none
you see that I won't have resize ability now anymore
but do you see this blue color border
we don't need this blue color border also
right
so for that reason
I'll add two more properties like you know border
to none
and also outline
whatever outline you are having to make it none
so when I do this
if you see I'm having task information I can type it down
as much I can want it
but I don't have ability to resize or do anything
as of now
okay let's let's add some background color to this one
let's add some background color to this
and let's give some height and width also
background color would be
let's say like kind of light color
DFE
for EA
let's say yeah
this is the color that we want to give you see here
this is the same color we are having
okay for this one let's give some background color
sorry height and width
let's say I have height
of
hundred percent
whatever height I'm having
and let's say I also have width of 75%
okay
so what I'm trying to say it is that
let's say when I do this I refresh
if you see I'm having height of 100%
whenever I give the height as 100% it will take
whatever it needs it to the content
when I give the width as 75 it is taking 75% of the screen width
you see here we needed if you consider this as a box
complete box we got the 100% height for this content
and 75% width for this text area content
is that clear why did I add that height and width
to this particular text area container
okay great guys
so I see one thumbs up it will be more clear
once I add few more properties to it
let's say wait and see
okay to increase the font of that information
that placeholder we see right
I'll use font size as 1.5 rem
let's use this and go back
let's see this yeah 1.5 rem
this is fine
okay
now once we have this
we'll go towards coloring this boxes
priority colors container now
going back
let's pick this CSS classes in order to avoid
mistakes and spelling so I'm trying to copy it
so I select this
and I give height again as 100%
since I consume the width of 75% for text area
I'll consume 25% for this colors
okay
now let's see this
you won't be able to see any difference
because colors are not even given a color
okay now
now once we have given height and width
to this one let's give some background color
that we have in common
and this would be again
let's say I have
this particular toolbox container background color
let's say background if I declare a variable as
background color
dark
okay and keep the smiling
and let's say I declare here where
and I'll say background color dark
okay and same thing I'll use this variable below
now once we give this background color
still it doesn't visible because for the elements
we want to we need to give some height and width
selecting this particular priority color
common thing I'm just updating this color
like height and width for each of element
let's say height is 3 rem
and width is 5 rem
why did I give a separate naming convention for this one
is that if you go and say evo color
we have height and width as different in the filter
and in the like the text part where we are covering
okay if you go back and see
this is what we got it
is that clear guys how we were able to replicate this part till now
guys any doubts in the CSS we have written till now
just I've used 3 paths I've given some default styles to it
so why did I change the name
I kept all the CSS classes as common
except common CSS class from color to the priority color
I gave it as priority color reason is
the height and width for this colors
and colors in the toolbox are different
because if you see evo
in the colors we have 1.5 rem and 3 rem
here we have 3 rem and 5 rem
that's the reason why I gave a different name
again I'll try to repeat each and everything
give me a minute once I complete this
next thing that we have to do is that
something moving on to this particular level container
let's select this container
priority colors container we already have this
we have given height width and this one
then let's make display as flex
again flex direction as column
we want each of them to be aligned in the column
because top to bottom
and then let's say align items to the center
and let's say justify content to space evenly
same thing
let's see this if this works
yeah they are moved towards this one
but if you see even though we gave 100% and 25
the width it is not being consumed as we expect
as we expect
any idea why this thing is not coming on right of this one
any idea guys why this is not coming in right of
block level elements right now let's say
if I select model container
model container
and if I make display as flex
let's see now this is covered
isn't it
first point is that
if I make display as flex
now this is covered isn't it
first point is clear like how did it work
like moving from bottom to the right
now I'll
use some properties guys
now do you remember
let's say do you remember what is VH
and VW
units of CSS
view height and view width
it's like viewport related height and width right
I hope the concept is clear for you all like if I'm going to use
let's say I say height of the container
whole container should be 50%
of view height of the screen
I'll also say that width
should be 45% of view width
do you understand
when I declare this height
and width are you able to understand what's going to happen
behind the scenes right fine
now also I'm going to
use a property now let's say
a background color I'll give us some background color as a
let's say light salmon
okay
once we give this now if you see I
was able to create this one
I don't really need to give
background color
as of now
like height is 50 VH
and the text area container is consuming 100 colors
also consuming 100
75% width is for area and 25% width is for
colors that's what it is looking like isn't it
now comes the role
of making it to look like a model
now do you guys help me out
this is the default place of
diff but if you see
when I'm creating when I'm trying to click button
here this is coming in between the
page but actual place
where I'm declaring is like when I'm writing
HTML is below the toolbox container
how can I move that from
one layer to the next layer
just answer my this question how can I move them from one layer
to the next layer position property right
and which position property would be really helpful for us to move them
around the whole page
absolute guys absolute
with respect to page right
with respect to page now let's say if I give
let's say if I give some properties like
going back here
relative is always going to be relative to body
even if I use your relative that would work fine
because relative would work with respect to parent
for this model anyways relative is like
body right according to body it will
that's also works fine but go with the right
yeah
if I give absolute and
let's say if I give like top
hey move it from top 30 percent
and move it from left
27 percent
let's see what is the change we are getting
do you see this
this is moved from top like
wherever the element was there from here to 30 percent
and from left 27 percent
this is clear to everyone right no one is having
any doubts how I am able to achieve this part
now this is on second layer right
what if let's say what if when we create a tickets right
when we create a tickets now if you see this tickets are there
this tickets are there but even when I am creating
this model this is coming showing on the top right on the
over the layer how we can ensure that this can be
this should be on the top set index right
right so I will use set index property
and I will say for safety side
I will make it as a file anyways by default
zero for the other cards I will make it as a file that works
so I hope this this property is also clear why
I am using this
now does it look same
guys isn't it
it's looking same isn't it
only one thing
is like whenever you selected there is a something hover
property that will cover it anyways in the code
while we are coding it ok I am not adding it here
wantedly I will cover it on hover how you can do it
ok now
now comes
once we have this
let's do something let's do this one
let's do some JS part let's do some JS
part coding
so before going to JS let's link
JS file ok let's say that I have
a script source and say
I have the script.js
now guys our interesting
task would be let's say I divide this
I pull this here
and now
the problem statement try to
listen this problem statement clearly now by default
even if I load it you can see the overlay
coming up right
everything is there right
we want to make this toggle
on click of this plus button on click of this plus button
we have to make it toggle like when you click there
when you again click plus it shouldn't be there
that is what we have to do now if you see
there is another thing like when I click outside
it doesn't go when I click only plus it goes off
ok on off like switch on switch off
ok now we have to achieve that
now you guys have learned DOM
operations now you guys have to suggest me how can
I do it because I am trying to listen some button
here how can I listen to this button
just think of it I will open the HTML part
you guys suggest me now if you suggest me quick
add an event listener
to which part to which part I should add
add a listener
button plus button right let's say I build
something like const button add button
and how can I
get an access to that button firstly how can I
get an access to that button
how can I
document dot query selector great
document dot query selector once I do
this query selector
let me move this code base bit this side once I have
this query selector what I have to do
I have to select add button
class that particular div
that we are targeting isn't it
no
second thing
which thing you are toggling
which container you are toggling what is the
we need a reference to this one also
model container let's say I create
a reference to that one also let's say const
model model
container
document dot query selector
model
container
this is clear right
now for add button
I am adding a listener click
now I have a problem statement
again now you guys suggested me that
add an event listener
ok
thank you
guys now you suggest me
how can I toggle this
display block great
but
for toggling we have to toggle display none right
and for this property model container
we have given a default property
if you go into model container
we have given a display as flex
we have to toggle between display flex and display none
right first point that point
is clear we have to toggle between display flex and display none
for on of model
great now now comes
the actual code part this is just a small
one liner problem statement add a toggle
event
if we don't have that
if you don't have that how would you toggle it
it's just a if else condition right if else
condition let's say if I
if I think of it this way in terms of
code let's say if I have a variable
add task
flag I'll say I'll I'm having a flag
I'll say by default it is false
ok and I'll say that
if add task flag
is equal equal to triple equal to true
then do something or else do
other thing
by doing this thing what I'll do is like I'll say model container
dot what should I do guys
if I want to change this style
I can use inline style right inline style
style block
style dot display
only if button is on then use
like this one or else use it not
flex
ok now when
user is clicking this when user is
clicking this we are toggling this add task button
let's say when we want to toggle this particular
thing I'll select this one I'll make it as
whatever value is there update that value
with the negation of that
is that clear guys like how did I
write this logic why did I use this part
ok no no going back
going back to style
going back to styles.css by default
do you think the style should be flex or style should be
none for this model
by default
by default the overlay shouldn't be available right
that point is clear no
let's say make none
ok by default this should be no
coming back so when
I say none when
user like let's debug this I'll show you
step by step ok when I debug this I'll show you step by step
going back to project now let's say click this
the task is working fine as of now
but I'll show you how this is working for the people
who didn't understand the conditional logic how it is working
whenever I refresh it
by default this code is not executed
until unless you click this button because this
button is listening to a click
when user clicks it only then this code will be
executed so a by default when the page
loads the flag value is false
we are making a negation and making true when we are making
a true the model whatever model
is there container which model we have here that's
element in that model container
we are toggling it we are adding inline style
that make it a display as a flex
if you see next line will be executed this one
and we are making it as a flex now
once I click this again if I click this again
now the true value will become false and it will make it display
as none is that clear guys
how that is working
ok so
if this part is done
any doubts guys any doubts in the whole class
that we have discussed till now any doubts in this whole class that we have
discussed
no right ok now let's say
I will make a comment as tool box creation
now what we will do is like we will create a
dummy ticket and flag part once again
open the unit again once again ok let me explain you
here it steps step by step by default
for this model container right whatever model container
is there default the style is none
so whenever your js file is loaded
the flag at task flag is false
so you won't be able to see anything on the screen
once user is clicking this button
I am making it as a true and once it is true
I am applying the display as flex else
I am making it as a none
is that clear like open the
ok simple
now let's build guys
if you see only the part
which thing is left is like
what we will do is that we will just build
this static ticket
we will make it dynamic in the upcoming classes
but we will build a simple html part
for that one though this html part will be coded
from javascript I will show you one basic ticket
how we can do it ok
now let's go and build a
div.main.ticket
container
let's say say this I have this container
let's say I create a ticket container
div.ticket
container
ok inside this ticket container
if you go and see we have three things
one is color one is ticket id then you have ticket
information right three things basically
top level three things now let's try to replicate
that one first would be
div.ticket
color
right next would be
div.ticket
id
guys if you are able to see this
if I am missing
anywhere BEM right BEM convention do let me know
if I am missing anywhere BEM convention
I hope you
you know address those
BEM convention mistakes that I have done in this class
hope you come back and let me know what mistakes I have done
ok that's the one homework that I am giving
only standards
would you be able to do that
CSS naming convention mistakes
ok just check that and let me know
where we can improve on
cool good
after ticket this one then I will have something like
tick task area
let's say task area
let's say I have some content as lower M
10 I save this
then I have something let's say id as some random gibberish
so this is what
a container looks like let's go back
this is our container
looks like right we haven't provided any ticket
color so we will do that using CSS
and let's see this how we can do it
ok first and foremost thing what I will do
is that I will create multiple tickets
let's say I copy paste this
multiple tickets
and created five tickets I believe
no I have five tickets now we will make it
you know CSS changes for this one
going back opening CSS
dividing screen into two parts
let's say we have this particular things
now let's get started with CSS
ok now
first and foremost thing
let's say tickets
I will apply some CSS
for the main container
main
ticket container
ok
now for the main ticket container
first and foremost thing if you see
these are aligned one after the other
in a horizontal task one is coming here task two is going next
horizontal alignment how we can do that
horizontal alignment
I think in terms of display only
that would work grid is like really for
top bigger screens where you set out the layout
but flex would work fine right as of now
this is not that complicated
one right
right let's say if I use display flex
I use display flex
and I simply give it
as justify content I mean content
should be along the center
and let's say also
if you see I will use
some property called as gap
gap property is used to
give space between each of its children
element whatever items are there flex items are there
on left right bottom top there should be like
two rem of gap this is coming from flex level
property this can be applied only when display flex for the particular
container is that clear guys
now if you see it applied to
rem of space on
between them
now once we applied this
once we applied this one thing I will do is that if there is
extra space right for the content if there is an extra
space I will use something like flex wrap
right thank you sir
so we will use flex wrap to make it
wrap the content now if you see it moved
bottom once we made it trap it moved one after
the other because why did it
move the other item to the down because it took the whole
space and consumed it we haven't given
it width and height yet so it is trying to consume
that thing is that clear like
it is saying that a whole space is there only
if the space is consumed then I will wrap it up now if
I if you want me to show it up how it can when it can
happen let's say I say lower m 100
sorry guys I think I got the code
if you see it's wrapping things down
going back editing this part
once this is done then
comes the main part once the container
part let's say this is what we will do for container
now comes the inside container
which is ticket container let's say
I select one ticket container
individual ticket container what will apply for individual
ticket container
going back to ticket container I will say
given height to the particular container as 12
and let's say I give a width
as 14
okay and if you see I will have
a background color of
coral a bit of orange one
right if you see in the tickets you will have
orange color background but will change for this
individual item level things okay
now once we did this
then go for a ticket color
ticket color let's
give it you know color for them
say height is
I'm giving a default color as of now
I'm not making it dynamic so I'm giving it
as a background color as a black
so since the color will be
dynamic in nature which will be keep changing on
click of button but I'm making it as a something
as long you know just for sake as of now
is that fine guys I'm making
a static black color
and I'll give some margin top here
so that it looks differentiated
10 pixel let's say 1 rem
unit
yeah fine now once this is done
is this clear guys till now what I've done it
nothing new right
any doubts
all right let's go for ticket
ID ticket
ID once you go
come for ticket ID let's say height is
2 rem for the ID part
and let's say I give a background color as
light
hello
let's see if this is
looking fine yeah it looks
odd let's make it yellow as of now I'll select
better color later
so this is yellow
now
do you see this anything missing yet
or we are able to replicate it whatever we want
guys
do you see this is
covered everything is covered right
lock icon edit button will add it dynamically
on each ticket
because if I go and add it right
let's say if even if I go to
font awesome let's say we pick font awesome
let's say I pick a lock
lock
I select this lock I copy
this
let's say
I didn't add it here
let's say I go and say
this place
I copy and paste it everywhere
after the content area
it shouldn't be inside this task area
lock should be in separate part
let me delete this
because this will be editable right editable
in nature once you click that button so button should be
yeah change
that same thing but we'll see
lock implementation completely in a different
way through JS actually
we'll code it down completely through JS so we'll see there
let's say I have this
three places
so
so I have done this
now if you go back to can man board you are
able to see the lock here but now if you have to move it to the
yeah
height will be covered from the parent right
now if you see when we say rem units relative
units now
for this one
do you see any
like parent ticket container in the ticket container
we have given a particular
height and width like
height and width now from that perspective
this rems will be calculated
is that clear Kabir
it's related to parent
now
guys can you
do CSS for lock
and move it to the bottom
right corner
anyone want to volunteer anyone want to volunteer I can unmute
them and we can do that or else you want to take it as a homework
and you want to do that anything works
but I want you to help me out
let's say somebody says
position absolute bottom zero right zero
let's let's do that
I have lock
position
absolute
bottom zero
right zero
do you
do you see this lock
came down completely
what could be the mistake guys
here we can use relative version now let's use relative version
if I use relative version
still the lock is sticking here
now let's say I select this lock
now this is the lock
position just a second guys
did I
CSS classes not applied
for everything
this is the lock
give me a second no if I
remove this bottom zero or anything it's not
working yet
add position relative to
previous part right let's say
I make it a main ticket container
as relative
position relative
and if I make below
one as absolute
let's see if this works
do you guys see this what just happened
okay I did a mistake again
I did it for the main container instead
of this part
I should make for ticket container
right
is this fine guys
display
flag justify and align
and would work fine
only if
you have multiple items
because you are applying it for container think from the container
perspective that those are applied to
container like
it's not it won't work for individual one element like
you are you need to think from children perspective
because this particular item is already a children
yeah so what we did position
right now when I select
absolute as a further lock
what's happening is that when you when I select absolute
absolute checks for the two conditions
first condition is like whether down
like when it goes over the chain
if there is any parent element with relative
if there is any parent with relative it will move
top right left bottom with respect to
that position but if there is no
parent element with position as related
it will move with respect to the top
most left place like if I show you
the chart that we have
that's the reason why I added a chart
here so that we can refer
right anytime we have confusion
if you see go for
absolute with respect
like starting position of element once applied with
respect to window top left or parent relative
is that clear Kabir
why we were we are adding relative to the container
then making it the lock item as absolute
so guys is everyone clear about what we
did it everything what we have wanted to achieve
and did we achieve everything
from the project HTML and CSS part
now all the functionality is remaining but
we added paint and structure to the application
isn't it
so I hope the concept is clear to everyone
now the one homework that I gave is you know
BEM convention I think I also added
inside the links
go for the BEM convention and explore it
and like
actually I would say right actually I would say that
hey
once your BEM convention is fixed
raise a PR to my
you know my kitab repo that I have it
I would be really happy if anyone does that
just only changing CSS names
just raise a small PR
and like changing the naming convention
if I put a lock it's not a right way
I try to defining lock lock is for what
lock is for ticket where you have mentioned ticket
think of in terms of that like naming convention should be
clear when you go into the style file
is that clear guys
would you be able to do that
go and read the BEM conventions
and I think I have talked about it
multiple times
you can you can go and see this
here CSS tricks I will pin this
I will also pin it
in the reading document
okay I won't be
addressing this issue guys you would be addressing it
I would be really happy if you can do that
okay
let's say class
today is a class number
what is a class number guys today I don't remember
if you go in JavaScript we have
covered 13th, 14th class
okay I have registered it can you please check and update git recordings
oh they didn't provide it guys
git
guys can you give me thumbs up thumbs down
if you have recordings added in your archive section
and even portfolio project that
we didn't cover this part portfolio project
I will push the code today but I want this
part to be also thought to you
okay I will ask the recordings to be added guys
like maybe I will recheck with the team
and I will get it added
okay I will get it added
so guys if everything is clear
can we start doubt session for today
so it's 2 hours 10 minutes
so I am starting doubt session guys if anyone have doubts
extra session that's a recording
will be available some bit so you can go through that
as for autocomplete
I have tab 9 starter package
if you see here I will start doubt session
and talk about it Kabir
so I am using tab 9 starter
if you see
this is tab 9 AI like
it generally suggest you the code
it understands it and suggest you
you can use actually better extensions
also I didn't update it
you can go for copilot
github copilot
like if you say 12.7 million people are using
you can go and use this copilot
that works fine
like it's a pay programming like let's say
you are working with someone you are having a friend
who is suggesting you what need to be done here
so I try to in my office I try to use as much
AI as it is like I can use it for
because today's
generation of development would be how much fast you can
you code it down rather than
I mean deliver your task rather than
how much challenge because if you know the basics
clearly right you will google it
the AI tools will suggest you those
small small petty things
syntax is not a big deal today
so that's the reason why I say that if someone in interview
for getting syntax I will help them out
I mean that's a basic thing anyone will figure out once they are in office
but it's just that they should be able to think like how they can do it
ok so you can use copilot
also something that I am using is
tab 9 I will show you
this thing I think I have
this is 6.9 million people
it needs a reload I will reload it
ok also
I have many actually you know
things installed like
mermaid and tailwind CSS thunder clients
I will help you out understanding one by one like
whenever things come
Cody let's explore Cody
yeah code assistant it's not that famous
yet Arun maybe sometimes in future
let's say Cody AI
152k people are using it
autocomplete features yeah you can use it you can search it
at my office I use something Amazon one
Amazon
yeah code whisper so they named it
as a code whisper because it whispers
your code I mean it whispers into your
like let's say onto your editor how you can code it
just giving them script right like
if you go for chat GPT you write it on
what you need but here it says
if you see here how can you do it if you see code whisper it's
really great one I mean I use it this one at office
in my office laptop I don't use tab 9 there
for this one you need access like
what we say enterprise level access
okay it does
security scans it does find vulnerabilities in your code
so it's really help you to write cleaner better
code
you can explore this guys this is like really
I mean if you the only thing
is like now even if you see
for this one right there only two lakhs people are using it
so
but you have to explore like what you can use it much
now
yeah it's up to you guys anything you can use it
anything else case anything else you want me to discuss on
so guys like if you enjoy
sessions please give us good ratings if you
have anything right you can write it down
constructive feedback I'll try to read it
through I'll make it you know better
I mean I'm just want to because it's
really heavy for us like if you get less ratings it's really
heavy for us like if you enjoyed write it down if you have any comments
do suggest me I'll work on it and
it's somewhere right it's a peer learning process I'm
working on one skill you are also working learning
on one skill so I'm trying to teach what I'm
good at maybe I'll work on my teaching spreader if you have
good comments works guys
great
okay thank you Kabir
so
hello guys then I'll close the session
for today we'll see again in next class I hope
you'll fix those BEM conventions
and come back and
because it's a thank you Kiran
yeah yeah needs a hands on right
that's the reason why I'm giving some when once you're trying
to go through BEM conventions right you will read it
you will have to go through the code
you will understand CSS you will update the CSS
so in a way you are reading the whole code because from
tomorrow once I write JavaScript in the next class
you will be feeling bit you know
lethargic to go through it how
how to develop more logic
on JS Sambit it comes with practice
for me if I say
directly from my experience right
directly writing in JS I too have
up to an extent knowledge like
because
more of my experience comes from frameworks knowledge
like where I worked on react and angular
also for some time but more on react
so on react specific knowledge I have
more but when it comes to JS right
at PayPal we have a Kraken framework on
so Kraken framework works like Kraken itself is
a full stack app full stack framework
where you write more on a server side logics on
client code where we write whole
node.js code because that Kraken framework is
compression of node.js and react so
on node.js you write clean JS so
on node.js and year and half I'm writing more JS
and I'm improving on it if I if you asked me
wanted of year back I would say that I'm 50
50 or 30 80 sort of thing 30 70 sort of
thing but it comes with practice as much as you
write it you'll get to know it from it
okay it comes with practice that's only the one thing that I can say
practice more
practice more like how can
you do it it's like same if you go for problem solving
open lead code solve problems
you can use JS logics there
but if you want to actually work on DOM manipulation
for DOM manipulation you have to do machine
learnings because machine learning problems I'll introduce
three four machine learning problems
three four machine learnings only will be solving after
this Kanban board once we cover
racing code then I'll give you a
list of machine coding like you know problems
that you can solve I'll push it this
something that we discussed right in the class I'll push
it onto the separate repo as a machine coding with
HTML.js also I'll give a list of
problems that you can solve you can contribute to that
repo that will be a practice like solving actual problems
because that is someone ping me
on whatsapp also do you find any website where we can
practice machine coding
like machine coding is related specific to HTML.js
DOM interaction right so for that
I'll help you out first we'll discuss few problems then I'll tell you
what problems you can solve and how you can solve
work somewhere
Opendra says CSS looks easy
it will take time Opendra I would
agree
we'll help you out some with that
CSS is like since we have learnt in
in better way right we are able to figure it out
in future classes when I'm working on react and
when I'm working on some more difficult projects
right then I won't be able to teach you CSS
like one by one property I'll be trying to paste
down the properties I'll skim through it I'll explain you
through it but I cannot go through it
completely because I'll be writing more and more logic
going at
yeah yeah CSS anything right
anything you use more more focus on one thing
you'll be being good at it so
as much as time you give it on it you'll become better on it
okay guys then
can we close the session
guys
I think I got cough I have to check it
thank you Opendra thank you all thank you all for attending
I hope to see you in the next class
so that we'll cover JS part for this one if you
completely understand this one project right you will be
surely having a good knowledge on these three parts
all of them thank you Sambit thank you Sambit
both Tripathi and Basant
thank you all see you in the next class
guys bye bye
I'll push the code guys see it I'm committing the code
okay bye bye
you